<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>RoverAI - How to build a rover</title>
    <link>https://roverai.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on RoverAI - How to build a rover</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>We are building a model of a Mars rover and we post our progress here.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://roverai.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Breadboarding electronics</title>
      <link>https://roverai.github.io/2019/11/breadboarding-electronics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://roverai.github.io/2019/11/breadboarding-electronics/</guid>
      <description>After not being able to properly cut the linear rods to proper lengths and make ridges in them due to a lack of a metalworking lathe, we decided to turn to Aliexpress for yet another thing that we originally planned to do differently.
We reached out to multiple suppliers of linear rods and asked if they could cut the rods to our pre-defined lengths as well as create adequate ridges for the e-clips that we have already bought.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spinning a wheel</title>
      <link>https://roverai.github.io/2019/10/spinning-a-wheel/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://roverai.github.io/2019/10/spinning-a-wheel/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hey, we are back after half a year! At this point, we have finished 3D printing all of the necessary parts. We have also received all the orders from Aliexpress and we started to look for a local swiss shop, where we could order screws, bolts and washers for a reasonable price. Then it was time to assemble the main body of the rover and try to spin a wheel.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3D print all the things!</title>
      <link>https://roverai.github.io/2019/03/3d-print-all-the-things/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://roverai.github.io/2019/03/3d-print-all-the-things/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At least half of the rover is going to be 3D printed. Considering the original author was printing for several weeks to make the whole rover, we decided to start early. This post outlines the details of transforming 3&amp;nbsp;kg of plastic wire into beautiful mechanical parts. You can skip this if you&amp;rsquo;re not into 3D printing. Scroll to the end of the post to see pictures.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ordering parts</title>
      <link>https://roverai.github.io/2019/03/ordering-parts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://roverai.github.io/2019/03/ordering-parts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The first step to every project nowadays is ordering everything you need in order to plan and design while waiting for delivery. Due to a different location, we had to do some modifications to the list of parts, while we also tried to push the total cost of the project down a bit. This summarizes what we ordered and why. A complete list of parts with the total budget will be available on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://roverai.github.io/parts&#34;&gt;List of parts&lt;/a&gt; page.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About this project</title>
      <link>https://roverai.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://roverai.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>The goal of our project is to build a motorized model of a Mars rover on a budget. The main goal is to see the Rocker-bogie mechanism in action, while trying to learn as many things as possible about robotics, electronics, image analysis and programming. We also intend to make the rover as smart as possible, but we will be happy if it moves without falling apart. We are powered by fascination with space exploration and a general love for science.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://roverai.github.io/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://roverai.github.io/contact/</guid>
      <description>You can contact us at roesel at gmail dot com or maksim dot eremchev at epfl dot ch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>List of parts</title>
      <link>https://roverai.github.io/parts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://roverai.github.io/parts/</guid>
      <description> This page contains a list of parts we used with specific links to the ordered items as well as their cost. We will update it as we receive and use individual items. Even though we try to be thorough, the list is most likely incomplete.
Costs Table with costs (including shipping and tax fees).
   Item Price Fees Link     Filament (PETG) 3 kg $48 $0 Lithuanian shop   Motors $7 $1 Aliexpress   Grand total $250 $250 $500    </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>