<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on RoverAI - How to build a rover</title>
    <link>https://roverai.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on RoverAI - How to build a rover</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>We are building a model of a Mars rover and we post our progress here.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://roverai.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Spinning a wheel</title>
      <link>https://roverai.github.io/2019/10/spinning-a-wheel/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://roverai.github.io/2019/10/spinning-a-wheel/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hey, we are back after half a year! At this point, we have finished 3D printing all of the necessary parts. We have also received all the orders from Aliexpress and we started to look for a local swiss shop, where we could order screws, bolts and washers for a reasonable price. Then it was time to assemble the main body of the rover and try to spin a wheel.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3D print all the things!</title>
      <link>https://roverai.github.io/2019/03/3d-print-all-the-things/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://roverai.github.io/2019/03/3d-print-all-the-things/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At least half of the rover is going to be 3D printed. Considering the original author was printing for several weeks to make the whole rover, we decided to start early. This post outlines the details of transforming 3&amp;nbsp;kg of plastic wire into beautiful mechanical parts. You can skip this if you&amp;rsquo;re not into 3D printing. Scroll to the end of the post to see pictures.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ordering parts</title>
      <link>https://roverai.github.io/2019/03/ordering-parts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://roverai.github.io/2019/03/ordering-parts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The first step to every project nowadays is ordering everything you need in order to plan and design while waiting for delivery. Due to a different location, we had to do some modifications to the list of parts, while we also tried to push the total cost of the project down a bit. This summarizes what we ordered and why. A complete list of parts with the total budget will be available on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://roverai.github.io/parts&#34;&gt;List of parts&lt;/a&gt; page.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>